Welcome back to Cleveland Browns Daily
brought to you by Valley Bet official
sports betting partner of your Cleveland
Browns. And it is an absolute treat to
bring in one of my great friends and one
of the great players on your Cleveland
Browns, Dewan Jones. Dwan, great to see
you. Looking spelt, looking good. How
the heck are you?
>> Uh, I'm doing good. Uh, just, you know,
just been grinding all offseason. Been
here. Uh, honestly, I just been in the
facility every day just taking care of
my body and just, you know, just trying
to lose weight and just be better for
next season.
>> So, I was going to say, you know,
offseason. Oh, where'd you go? I know
work cuz I've seen you walk out every
day. You get picked up and you go about
your business. What has this been like?
Because it just seems, you know, my
heart goes out for you. It just seems so
unfair. Three years in a row, a season
ending injury. It feels like you're
rehabbing probably as much or more than
you're playing the game that you love.
How has it been? And mentally, you know,
to know that at least you're through it
now. What's it just what's this been
like? Um, it's unfortunate, you know,
but I just sometimes I just talk it up
to the part of the game, you know, it's
just it happens like and you just got to
move on and put your head down, you
know, don't get in a deep hole because
once you do that, you can't really go
back. And I just try to like take it one
day at a time. That's the only thing I
can really do. And that's kind of what
my mom tells me and my family tells me,
you know, you know, I kind of told them
I let them down and, you know, I really
was hurt and they was just like, you
know, you didn't let us down. Like, you
know what I mean? Like it's unfortunate.
And, you know, but
>> it's ridiculous. I just I just
>> I remember watching and I'm like you
have got to be kidding me.
>> I just want to play, man. And that's,
you know, everybody knows I compete and
I just I just want to play as much as
possible.
>> Man, you've been excellent whenever you
have played and that's why we got to get
you healthy and get you out there. You
mentioned, you know, trying to get your
body right. You I know you've posted on
Instagram, but what do you what are you
at right now?
>> Uh I'm at 360 uh 359. So I'm in that
range.
>> 359. Yeah.
>> You know, I got just keep it there.
>> What do you want to be? I want to finish
the summer at like 350, 355, you know,
somewhere in that range. So hopefully
that's very doable. Yeah. You know, so
that's not far off and I just want to
shoot for that goal.
>> It's just you got to lose like if you're
let's go 359 right now. So get 350, you
got to lose nine pounds. That's like 3%.
>> It's hard to maintain it though. You
know, you get there. I know. You get
there and you be like, but you know, I
just it's a big year this year. So I
know I got a lot of expectations and
yeah, I just want to live up to it. So,
you're coming off this injury
change. New head coach Todd Monkin.
What's your interaction with him been
like and and you know he's a guy and
we're going to play a clip from Seth
Rollins today or maybe we already have.
I don't know if we played it already
because we're kind of in this weird time
continuum right now, but where he hears
Todd Monk and he's like I you know what
I'm in on the Browns because he's no
nonsense. for you getting to sit down
and talk with Todd, what's that been
like and knowing that he's been a guy
who's had big offensive linemen on his
offensive lines in the past?
>> Um, it's been great. He uh pulled me to
the side. Um, I was walking past him
going to our first team meeting and he
just or offensive meeting. He just was
like, you know, I appreciate you, you
know, just being here all off all off
all off all off all off all off all off
all off all off all off all offseason
like I've seen you your work and what
you've done like like that doesn't go
unnoticed and you know just keep working
and just keep building muscle and body
mass and you know that's really like I
appreciate that knowing like you know my
work is being seen and you know I don't
do it for no praise but you know just
knowing that my coach see here every day
and just working.
>> People talk sometimes about you know
like a young quarterback right and
they're like oh man this guy's had four
different offensive coordinator in his
first four years. Well, you are now
going to have four different offensive
line coaches in your first four years.
You started with an absolute legend in
Bill Callahan. Well, now you got another
absolute legend in George Warhop. What's
kind of that interaction been? And and
knowing that you got guys like Titus
Howard who's come in, who's played for
him, Joe Thomas, Joe Thomas played for
him and they all kind of say the same
thing that this guy's going to get the
best out of you, especially young
players who are talented and that that's
you. Young player, very talented.
>> Um, you know, me and coach Warhog, we've
talked a lot. uh he's came in, stopped
down during my lifts and you know even
just from the past couple of days and
we've got along and it's just it's
really good to pick his brain and just
see where he's at and he's just a you
know older guy but and you know he
shocked me a lot with what he was
talking about and just
>> he shocked you,
>> you know, just different variations of
what him and you know other coaches do
and just what you know going back to
Bill just seeing what Bill does, you
know, a little bit different and it's
just dope just to see a different
perspective of it.
>> Uhhuh.
you have had also not only the four
different offensive line coaches, but
then assistant offensive line coaches
and you started with one of the most
jacked offensive line coaches in the
history of the league and Scott Peters
and now you've got another absolute unit
as an assistant offensive line coach.
>> Uh Bobby Johnson, he's been good. Uh he
actually was there at my proday and so
like you know just seeing him with full
circle was pretty crazy. Uh, and I think
he I want to say one of my coaches was
his teammate or no, he coached one of my
coaches, coach Fry, and then one of my
coaches I want to say was his teammate
or something like that. So, just having
Yeah, just having the connections and
stuff like that is just dope.
>> Have they talked to you at all about
like their expectations for you or the
goals? You know, you it's easy pretty
easy to look at our offensive line right
now and say, "Okay, left tackle still
feels like let's go, Dand." Uh, I
haven't heard nothing from that aspect,
but you know, my main thing is just to
keep my head down. Um,
>> you know, but I have no no control over
that, but for the most part, I just know
that I get to go play football soon.
>> Yeah. Which you're excited. Big smile on
your face. You're excited about right
there. Uh, for you, we saw the video of
you playing hoops. How does that come
about? And is that something you have to
say, "Hey, I'd like to go play some
hoop." Like, how does that come about
for you?
>> Uh, no. And you know, a lot of people
just be like, you know, you should let
your body recover. And I do for the most
part. I go home and I recover and just
chill. And you know, I'm on I have
downtime and you know, I need to get my
legs going. And
>> yeah,
>> you know, it's just
that's the main thing is just keeping me
in shape. And honestly, just cardio. I
mean, I may not go down all the time on
defense or offense, but I'm getting up
and down, so it don't matter. You know,
I'm not
>> out there trying to get a contract or
nothing. And so like you know people
would be like you're going to get hurt.
I'm like I'm I'm fine. I've done this
for a while. Like just let me do me and
you do you.
>> Yeah. I like though you get the put back
and then you give a little bit less.
Yeah.
>> They were all
>> Are those like your buddies uh
>> from home?
>> One of them was uh like one of the
guards that was like one of my best
friends. And then a couple guys are from
Cleveland that you know he's made
connections with and you know that was
just the the team he selected and you
know we're going to run it back this
week. So fun.
>> Hopefully it's a clip this week or
something like that. It's we play early
at three.
>> Okay. And I like I like again I like
after the score get a little bow up on
somebody. What's your what's your
favorite? You get the ball on the block.
Is that where you want to get the ball
and then what's your what's your go-to?
>> I want to go right hook. I want to get
to that right hook and I want
>> like a jump hook or a sky.
>> I want to get to a jump hook. I want to
get to a jump hook and if I can't get to
that, I want to dunk on you.
>> I I want to turn my shoulders at the
basket and put the ball in the rim. Do
you know the name Kevin Willis?
>> Uh yes, I know Kevin Willis rappers.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Well, and a jump hook
aficionado. He was a very ripped guy.
>> I'm more so on the shack side. Yeah. I'm
I got long arms and we were watching NBA
the other day and we were just hearing
everybody's wingspan and they went down
and it was like KD, you know, 611 75
wingspan. I was like dang
>> Donovan Mitchell has a 610 wingspan.
>> But you know those guys 75 wingspan? Me.
So I was like I was like that's pretty
crazy that like you know my
>> Yeah.
>> You know 67.
>> Yeah. You know I'm 6'8.
>> 68. Sorry. Don't want to short change
it.
>> No no no. So just you know just my arms
being that long and just comparing it to
the NBA players. It's like it's crazy.
You know they that they go out there and
do the profession just like us.
>> Well that's one of the things like when
Joe Thomas talked to he's like you got
this. Don't even get near you.
>> Go out there. Go out there and get them.
How excited are you mentioned and then
we were talking obviously hoops but
you're excited to get back to to
football. What is it that you miss the
most about football?
>> Uh, I mean, practice of course, you
know, you don't want to skip that. You
know, it starts right there. Uh, just
going back to my grind, going against
the the guys. That's what gets you ready
for Sundays. And then obviously Sundays,
it doesn't get better than that. You
know, just the drive down, seeing all
the fans and the parking lot in MUN. It
it's just unreal. You know, some people
probably don't really get to like see
that. And just, you know, like those
fans been out there for years and I I
cherish that, you know, just going out
there on Sundays. What do you think
about the fact that there's a good
chance that four of the top 10 picks in
the NFL draft this year are going to be
Buckeyes? There's there's a good chance
that maybe a Buckeye's going to make his
way here to the Cleveland Browns at
number six.
>> You know, I have no issue with that. I'm
going to say oh every time and hopefully
they say I back and you know, we going
to keep it rocking. They going to be on
the team with us. But you know, I have
no selection.
>> Of course. Of course. But it would be it
would be nice, you know, just to
hopefully play either one of my former
teammates or just, you know, one of the
young guys that I seen come in.
>> Yeah, it's it's an unbelievable factory
and it's kind of like, hey guys, maybe
we should have we're going to have all
these top and if Jeremiah was in the
draft, if Julian S was in the draft,
maybe they have six of the top 10. They
got we got to get that national
championship back here going.
>> We got to get that back. It's all right,
though.
>> So, we were talking about this with Bo.
There are some people in Columbus who
are like just happy this year because
they beat Michigan the year four. Don't
beat Michigan, but win the national
championship. Winning national
championship is still better. Yeah.
>> Um,
>> so you have to think about it's not an
automatic.
>> I'm big on beating T North just cuz I
ain't beat him. I mean, yeah, I beat him
my freshman year, but I didn't really
play. So, like I'm big on beating like
you work your whole 365 for that to beat
them, you know what I mean? When we
don't go out there and perform, it just
looks bad. And so, I was kind of happy.
I also was sad though that we lost to
IU. And being from Indiana,
>> just just hear seeing all the the fake
IU fans come out the woodworks and stuff
like that. That really it really took me
for a dive.
>> How about this though? Think about think
about if you were to tell
when did you first start when were you
first a fan of football and like aware
of college football?
>> I probably didn't know college football
till probably like middle school maybe.
I was really like I'm big on basketball
just cuz I come I come from a basketball
state but you know I ended up realizing
that in middle school you know that was
like a big thing like
>> okay so if you were to tell middle
school Dwan Jones that Indiana won the
national championship in football would
you be like no way impossible
>> I mean I'm from Indiana and you know
they won a national championship before
they won a basketball championship the
last time they won one was what 85 and
that's you It was Isaiah Thomas. So
that's that's crazy. So I don't know. I
>> It's It's impossible.
>> I wouldn't believe it. It's
>> You went to Ohio State. The fact that
the Indiana teams that you played by the
time that you've been in the NFL for now
going three years, they're going to win
a national a national championship.
>> I didn't see it by long.
>> Beat the Buckeyes twice.
>> Beat them twice.
>> Beat Miami
like Ind with no five stars. Zero. Not a
single one. Like it's it's one of the
most improbable college stories, sports
stories period,
>> ever. You know, they could probably
never win again. But they won national
championship. It's marked on there that
the Indian Hooers won a national
championship
>> and beat
>> some people on the way there. Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's it's crazy. So, basketball
state, obviously, we get to go to to
Indie for our uh the combine every year,
which is always fun. And, you know, on
the way out, we sometimes Bo, I know,
has stopped and got some shots up there
at the Hooers. gym. Is that something
that you ever did?
>> I got invited before to the Turkhoon
versus Hickory game um in a high school.
So, I actually played on that court
before.
>> Wow.
>> What was that like?
>> It's by far one of the best experiences
I had. Uh it's small in there. It gives
you just like the movie though, like it
just reminds you everything. The
>> the locker room was the real like
>> locker room
>> shocker. You know, I'm tall. I'm 6'8. Uh
I played with I want to say Trace
Jackson Dave was on the other team and
uh so he was on the other team and we
were both 69 just ducking our heads. You
know there's a couple NBA guys on our
team and so you know just it was just
crazy just to be there and then have
that memory for forever and I could tell
my kids I played in the Hickory Gym. You
know I I ride past all the time and just
be like you know Milan like that's
that's history right there.
>> Unbelievable. That had to be almost I'm
a big golfer right? So for me I got to
play St. Anders once, which is where
golf was invented. And I feel like it
was kind of like magical, spiritual a
little bit. I imagine that had to be
what it was like to play in that gym.
>> It's very similar. Like for me, I'm so I
would want to go to Springfield, like
you said. I would want to see what
Springfield is like and playing at the,
you know, the old basketball where it
has a uh what is it? Just the
>> the peach basket.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I would want to see
that, you know. That's dope.
>> Yeah, for sure. I'm actually going to
your neck of the woods in a little bit.
Well, the state of India French lick
where obviously the birthplace labor
play a little chase the small ball.
>> That's a that's a really nice course.
I've never been there but
>> I've heard it's like it's awesome. Are
you swinging the six at all?
>> No, I'm terrible.
>> Terrible. You get in the sim at all?
>> I am bad. No,
>> I do. I do have a sim and it's not that.
It's racing. I be on the races.
>> So, you have one of the like full on
like
>> I don't set I don't One of my buddies
does. He uh he stays with me. He got the
full setup and um I got just like the
normal just willing. Does he have the
one though where like it can like pull
like
>> No, those are those are expensive.
Deshan has that one. Desan got that one,
but um I just got the like the normal
one. We try to keep it like realistic
and stuff like that.
>> So I try to like clear my mind with
doing stuff like that. I can't get into
golfing. I'm not
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> It's not my strong suit.
>> My cousin is a huge racing fan and I
mean he goes he's been to Indie a bunch
times. He loved Indie Car and he likes
Formula 1. Those are like his Formula
1's probably his favorite.
>> Oh no. I don't know. We got to get him
out of there. We got to get him.
>> But he's he likes Indie Car.
>> Yeah, I love Indie Car. Like
>> what's your favorite?
>> My favorite is NASCAR.
>> So he's not as much of a NASCAR.
>> I think it's more it's more relatable to
football and just what we do every day.
I think that's like the main thing.
>> Um Indie car is just so fast.
>> That's like almost basketball. I feel
like
>> yeah,
>> you know, like it's like the change of
pace and you know, once some or I would
say baseball maybe once somebody's
leading, you know, that's normally going
to be the leader and that's who's going
to win. So I I kind of treat it like
that and just the way
>> I don't know. I kind of keep keep it
like the game inside the game.
>> 401 is cool, but it's it feels like if
you have the best car, you're going to
win.
>> Go back to that. You're going to just
you're just going to stay up front and
it's going to get boring and you know,
who wants to just watch the same person
lead the whole time?
>> Every Yeah. The team, right? When we
watch NASCAR, it's a new leader coming
out as pit strategies. Like I watched
Martinsville and I want to say Gust, I
forget his name, but um Chase Elliot,
his crew chief, he made him stay out and
they got tires on the next cycle. And
that's basically what won the race
because he got the bottom line. He got
to pick the line on which you want to
choose and and after that I mean then he
was behind him and he kind of
>> you know tried to bump him and do
whatever he could but his tires weren't
that good because he got outsmarted you
know that's just simple.
>> All right so you're obviously a
professional football player so you're
living a dream clearly but in an
alternate universe if you could be the
best driver on NASCAR or a first team
allNNBA player which would you pick? Oh,
that's tough.
>> That wasn't supposed to be easy.
>> Oh, that's tough.
>> Or or I'll throw another one in there
because I also know that you love
wrestling. You could be like John Cena.
>> If I could
It'll probably be
>> actually The Rock. We'll say The Rock.
He's the coolest.
>> The No, you had it right with John Cena.
No, you had it right. You had it right.
Uh I'd probably do I don't know. That's
tough. That is
>> It was supposed to be hard.
>> I know. I'll probably go NBA though.
>> NBA just cuz you know they got they get
their face shown every day. You know,
people are already rating and starting
to drop for WWE and it's
>> it's sad, but you know, hopefully it
picks up some.
>> You could have been like though at the
you could have been at the peak of the
the business.
>> Not me. I don't I don't want to be
another just big guy in WWE and um yeah,
NASCAR.
>> It's not that many 68 guys that drive
cars. I'd rather own it. I'd rather be
the Michael Jordan of it
>> by and may maybe someday you will be.
Dwan, always a pleasure. Glad the
rehab's going well. Glad you like you're
digging the message from not only Todd
Monkin but George Warhop and you look
great and we're excited to you know see
the content keep coming but also see you
back on the field and and making great
plays for this team. Yes,
>> sir. Thank you for having me. All right,
Dawan Jones. Absolutely love this kid.
We'll be back for more Climbrrons daily
brought you by Valley Bet right after